Guide to the Wanda Gifford Photographs 1948-1958
Oregon State University Libraries, University Archives
- Unnumbered Photographs, 1949-1958; Series II; 581 negatives and 163 prints
  - Snow covered lane or driveway (Box 6)
  - Man purchasing a newspaper?, downtown Salem (Box 6)
  - Group of newly naturalized citizens? (Box 6)
  - Broccoli field (Box 6)
  - Pear picking near Roseburg, Oregon (Box 6)
  - Young girl with strawberries in carrier, 2 prints (Box 6)
  - Daffodil field (Box 6)
  - Tractors in fields, 3 prints (Box 6)
  - Woman standing next to lake in Rockies or Tetons?
    - 2 prints (Box 6,)
    - 3 oversize prints (Box 74, 76)
  - Little girl holding doll, oversize print (Box 76)
- Color Transparencies, circa 1950s; Series III; 96 color transparencies
  Series III consists of positive color transparencies made by Wanda Gifford; several of the images were probably taken by her son, Ben L. Gifford. The images depict landmarks in Salem, Oregon, such as the capitol, courthouse, and state buildings; farms, orchards, and gardens; and Oregon scenic views. The Oregon scenes include Multnomah Falls, Mt. Hood, Three Sisters, the Wallowa Mountains, the Oregon coast, and the John Day fossil beds area. The series also includes color images of Mt. Baker, Glacier National Park, and the Canadian Rockies. Most of the transparencies are 4x5 format; only a few (5) are 5x7 format.
  - Oregon State Capitol, Salem, 2 4x5 color transparencies (Box 65)
  - Murals in State Capitol, 8 4x5 color transparencies (Box 65)
  - Old Marion County Courthouse, Salem, Oregon, 4x5 color transparency (Box 65)
  - Rhododendrons & old Marion County Courthouse, Salem, Oregon, 4x5 color transparency (Box 65)
  - State Forestry Building, 2 4x5 color transparencies (Box 65)
    See also image 0157 in Series I.
  - Garden scene at the home of prominent orchardist Paul Wallace, Salem, Oregon, 4x5 color transparency (Box 65)
    See also prints in Series II.
  - "Tulip Border" at home of Elmer R. Worth, Salem, Oregon, 2 4x5 color transparencies (Box 65)
  - Rhododendrons and country estate of Ronald Jones near Salem, Oregon, 4x5 color transparency (Box 65)
  - Close-up of rhododendron blooms, 4x5 color transparency (Box 65)
  - Field of daffodils near Salem, Oregon, 2 4x5 color transparencies (Box 65)
  - Azalea garden, Silverton, Oregon, 4x5 color transparency (Box 65)
  - Red barn with cherry blossoms in background, 4x5 color transparency (Box 65)
  - Apple tree ready for harvest, 2 4x5 color transparencies (Box 65)
    Includes image of child eating apple.
  - Garden scene (roses), 4x5 color transparency (Box 65)
  - Winter sunset on the Willamette River, Salem, Oregon, 4x5 color transparency (Box 65)
  - Boats at docks, 4x5 color transparency (Box 65)
    See also image 1198 in Series I.
  - Formal gardens at Alderman Farm near Dayton, Oregon, 4x5 color transparency (Box 65)
  - Registered Jersey cows owned by Frank Gratsinger, Gervais, Oregon, 4x5 color transparency (Box 65)
  - Registered Guernsey cows owned by R. A. Tansey, Salem Oregon, 3 4x5 color transparencies (Box 65)
  - Hereford cows and calves owned by Henry A. Thiessen, Jefferson, Oregon, 4x5 color transparency (Box 65)
  - Putting up sileage on Lane Bros. Farm, Dayton, Oregon, 2 4x5 color transparencies (Box 65)
    Probably taken by Ben L. Gifford; see also images 9I-8 and 9I-9 in the Ben L. Gifford Photographs (P 218-SG 5).
  - Sheep grazing, 4x5 color transparency (Box 65)
  - Shilly Lenocker picking strawberries in Elgin Lucas patch, Hubbard, Oregon, May, 29, 1951; 4x5 color transparency (Box 65)
    Probably taken by Ben L. Gifford; see also image 11K-8 in the Ben L. Gifford Photographs (P 218-SG 5).
  - Crates of freshly picked strawberries, 4x5 color transparency (Box 65)
  - Close-up of strawberries, 4x5 color transparency (Box 65)
  - Trees in bloom, 4x5 color transparency (Box 65)
  - Young woman and rhododendrons, 2 4x5 color transparencie (Box 65)
  - Multnomah Falls, circa 1950
    - Path to falls, 5x7 color transparency (Box 68)
    - Parking lot and falls, 5x7 color transparency (Box 68)
  - Pasture, barn and Mt. Hood, 5x7 color transparency (Box 68)
    #1414
  - Lake and Mt. Hood, 2 4x5 color transparencies (Box 65)
  - Orchards in bloom; Mt. Hood in distance, 4 4x5 color transparencies (Box 65)
  - Little girl standing in blooming orchard; Mt. Hood in background, 4x5 color transparency (Box 65)
  - Orchard in bloom; mountain in background, 4x5 color transparency (Box 65)
  - Orchard in bloom next to highway; mountain in background, 4x5 color transparency (Box 65)
  - Depoe Bay, Oregon, 4x5 color transparency (Box 65)
  - Alsea Bay Bridge at Waldport, Oregon, 4x5 color transparency (Box 65)
  - Lighthouse and beach at Heceta Head, 4x5 color transparency (Box 65)
  - McCullough Memorial Bridge on Highway 101, North Bend, Oregon, 3 4x5 color transparencies (Box 65)
    See also images 1169, 1172, 1175, and 1178 in Series I.
  - "The Lookout" (Lookout Rock, Curry County?) along the Oregon Coast, 4x5 color transparency (Box 65)
  - Coastal view from highway, 4x5 color transparency (Box 65)
    Labeled #2083.
  - Rocks along the Oregon Coast, 4x5 color transparency (Box 65)
    Labeled #2088.
  - Woman sitting on beach, Oregon Coast, 5x7 color transparency (Box 68)
  - Child fishing in river, Central Oregon?; mountains in background, 5x7 color transparency (Box 68)
  - Metolius River in Central Oregon; Mt. Jefferson in background, 2 4x5 color transparencies (Box 65)
    See also image 0991 in Series I.
  - The Three Sisters
    - As seen from Scott Lake, high in the Cascade Mountains, 4x5 color transparency (Box 65)
      See also image 0989 in Series I.
    - Woman sitting on a stone fence, 4x5 color transparency (Box 65)
      See also image 0994 in Series I.
  - Cathedral Domes, John Day State Park, 4x5 color transparency (Box 65)
  - Sheep Mountain, John Day River, and fossil bed formations, 4x5 color transparency (Box 65)
  - John Day River? and rock formations, 2 4x5 color transparencies (Box 65)
  - Wallowa Lake, 4x5 color transparency (Box 65)
  - Fishing in the Wallowa Mountains, Oregon, 4x5 color transparency (Box 65)
  - Mt. Baker from Baker Lake, Washington, 5 4x5 color transparencies (Box 65)
    See also images 1006-1007 and 1009 in Series I.
  - Glacier National Park, Montana
    - Two Medicine Lake, 2 4x5 color transparencies (Box 65)
    - Going To The Sun Highway, as seen from Logan Pass at the high point of the highway, 4x5 color transparency (Box 65)
    - Swift Current Falls and Grinnell Peak, 4 4x5 color transparencies (Box 65)
    - Upper St. Mary's Lake, 4x5 color transparency (Box 65)
    - St. Mary's River, 2 4x5 color transparencies (Box 65)
  - Canadian Rockies
    - Lake Louise, 2 4x5 color transparencies (Box 65)
    - Ten Peaks?, 4x5 color transparency (Box 65)
      See also image 0759 in Series I.
  - Unidentified lakes, 2 4x5 color transparencies (Box 65)